Guide to the Census Non-Population Schedules, 1850-1880
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Census Non-Population Schedules 1850-1880
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
United States. Bureau of the Census
50 linear feet Extent: 134 Items
Collection contains the original returns compiled by the census enumerator. Schedules exist in four main categories: agriculture, manufacturing, "defective, dependent, and delinquent classes," and social statistics. The 7th (1850); 8th (1860); 9th (1870); and 10th (1880) censuses are included, while the states covered are Colorado, District of Columbia, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Tennessee, and Virginia, with scattered records for Montana, Nevada, and Wyoming. In many cases the returns are not complete. For a given schedule all counties of a state may not be represented.
RL.00204
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Census Non-Population Schedules, 1850-1880 were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer from the Headquarters of the Daughters of the American Revolution in Washington, D.C. in 1934.
Collection Overview
Original census returns as collected by the census enumerators containing abundant detailed information on the various questions covered. The following states and schedules are in the collection, either in part or in full, by counties which constitute the last item shown in the following list:
Colorado: agriculture, 1870, Arapahoe to Weld; manufacturing, 1870, Arapahoe to Weld; social statistics, 1870, Arapahoe to Weld; agriculture, 1880, Arapahoe to Weld; defective classes, 1880, Arapahoe to Weld; manufacturing, 1880, Arapahoe to Summit.
District of Columbia: agriculture, manufacturing, and social statistics, 1850, 1860, 1870; agriculture, 1880; detectives, delinquents, and dependents, special manufacturing schedules, 1880; indigent and pauper, 1880.
Georgia: agriculture, 1850, Appling to Putnam; social statistics, 1850, Baker to Wilkinson; agriculture, 1860, Appling to Worth; social statistics, 1860, Appling to Worth; agriculture, 1870, Appling to Worth; social statistics, 1870, Appling to Worth; agriculture, 1880, Appling to Worth; defective, delinquent, and dependent classes, 1880, Appling to Worth; manufacturing, 1880, Appling to Worth.
Kentucky: agriculture, 1850, Adair to Woodford; manufacturing, 1850, Adair to Woodford; social statistics, 1850, Adair to Woodford; agriculture, 1860, Adair to Woodford; manufacturing, 1860, Adair to Woodford; social statistics, 1860, Adair to Woodford; agriculture, 1870, Adair to Woodford; agriculture (recapitulation), 1870, Allen to Woodford; manufacturing, 1870, Adair to Woodford; social statistics, 1870, Adair to Woodford; agriculture, 1880, Adair to Woodford; defective, delinquent dependent classes, 1880, Adair to Woodford; manufacturing, 1880, Adair to Woodford.
Louisiana: agriculture, 1850, Ascension to Washington; social statistics, 1850, Assumption to Washington; agriculture, 1860, Ascension to Winn; social statistics, 1860, Ascension to Winn; agriculture, 1870, Ascension to Winn; agriculture (recapitulation), 1870, Ascension to Winn; social statistics, 1870, Ascension to West Feliciana; agriculture, 1880, Ascension to Winn; defective, delinquent, and dependent classes, 1880, Ascension to Winn; manufacturing, 1880, Ascension to Winn.
Montana: agriculture, 1880.
Nevada: agriculture, 1880.
Tennessee: agriculture, 1850, Anderson to Wilson; manufacturing, 1850, Anderson to Wilson; social statistics, 1850, Anderson to Wilson; agriculture, 1860, Anderson to Wilson; manufacturing, 1860, Monroe to Wilson; social statistics, 1860, Anderson to Wilson; agriculture, 1870, Anderson to Wilson; manufacturing, 1870, Anderson to Lewis; social statistics, 1870, Anderson to Wilson; agriculture, 1880, Anderson to Wilson; defective, dependent, and delinquent classes, 1880, Anderson to Wilson; manufacturing, 1880, Anderson to Wilson.
Virginia: free inhabitants, slaves, deaths, agriculture, manufacturing, social statistics, 1860, Halifax.
Wyoming: agriculture, 1880.
With the exception of the Colorado material, all records are also on microfilm.
[Description taken from Guide to the Cataloged Collections in the Manuscript Department of the William R. Perkins Library, Duke University (1980)]
Contents of Collection
- Colorado Census Schedules, 1870, 1880, (6 volumes)
  - Colorado: Agriculture: Arapahoe - Weld (1870) (Volume ff:2401)
  - Colorado: Agriculture: Arapahoe - Weld, recapitulation (1870) (Volume ff:2402)
  - Colorado: Manufacturing: Arapahoe - Weld (1870) (Volume ff:2403)
  - Colorado: Social Statistics: Arapahoe - Weld (1870) (Volume ff:2404)
  - Colorado: Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes: Arapahoe - Weld (1880) (Volume ff:2406)
  - Colorado: Manufacturing: Arapahoe - Summit (1880) (Volume ff:2407)
- District of Columbia Census Schedules, 1850, 1860, 1870, 1880, (4 volumes)
  - District of Columbia: Agricultural, manufacturing, social statistics (1850, 1860, 1870) (Volume ff:2409)
  - District of Columbia: Agriculture (1880) (Volume ff:2410)
  - District of Columbia: Defectives, dependents, and delinquents; Special manufacturing schedules (1880) (Volume ff:2411)
  - District of Columbia: Pauper and indigent (1880) (Volume ff:2412)
- Georgia Census Schedules, 1850, 1860, 1870, 1880, (27 volumes)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Appling - Crawford (1850) (Volume ff:2413)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Dade - Houston (1850) (Volume ff:2414)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Irwin - Putnam (1850) (Volume ff:2415)
  - Georgia: Social Statistics: Baker - Wilkinson (1850) (Volume ff:2416)
  - Georgia: Agriculture (1860) (Volume ff:2418)
  - Georgia: Social Statistics: Appling - Worth (1860) (Volume ff:2420)
  - Georgia: Agriculture (1860) (Volume SS:105)
  - Georgia: Agriculture (1860) (Volume SS:97)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Appling - Jackson (1870) (Volume ff:2421)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Jasper - Worth (1870) (Volume ff:2422)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Appling - Worth, recapitulation (1870) (Volume ff:2423)
  - Georgia: Social Statistics: Appling - Worth (1870) (Volume ff:2424)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Appling - Butts (1880) (Volume ff:2425)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Calhoun - Clay (1880) (Volume ff:2426)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Clayton - Dodge (1880) (Volume ff:2427)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Dooly - Franklin (1880) (Volume ff:2428)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Fulton - Haralson (1880) (Volume ff:2429)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Harris - Laurens (1880) (Volume ff:2430)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Lee - Miller (1880) (Volume ff:2431)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Milton - Pickens (1880) (Volume ff:2432)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Pierce - Talbot (1880) (Volume ff:2433)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Taliaferro - Walker (1880) (Volume ff:2434)
  - Georgia: Agriculture: Walton - Worth (1880) (Volume ff:2435)
  - Georgia: Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes: Appling - Harris (1880) (Volume ff:2436)
  - Georgia: Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes: Hart - Worth (1880) (Volume ff:2437)
  - Georgia: Manufacturing: Appling - Hall (1880) (Volume ff:2438)
  - Georgia: Manufacturing: Hancock - Worth (1880) (Volume ff:2439)
- Kentucky Census Schedules, 1850, 1860, 1870, 1880, (40 volumes)
  - Kentucky: Social Statistics: Adair - Woodford (1850) (Volume ff:2400)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Adair - Carter (1850) (Volume ff:2440)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Casey - Grayson (1850) (Volume ff:2441)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Green - Lawrence (1850) (Volume ff:2442)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Letcher - Nelson (1850) (Volume ff:2443)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Nicholas - Woodford (1850) (Volume ff:2444)
  - Kentucky: Manufacturing: Adair - Woodford (1850) (Volume ff:2445)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Adair - Breathitt (1860) (Volume ff:2446)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Bracken - Fleming (1860) (Volume ff:2447)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Floyd - Nicholas (1860) (Volume ff:2448)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Kenton - Montgomery (1860) (Volume ff:2449)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Ohio - Woodford (1860) (Volume ff:2450)
  - Kentucky: Manufacturing: Adair - Woodford (1860) (Volume ff:2451)
  - Kentucky: Social Statistics: Adair - Woodford (1860) (Volume ff:2452)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Adair - Hancock (1870) (Volume ff:2453)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Christian - Lyon (1870) (Volume ff:2454)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Madison - Pendleton (1870) (Volume ff:2455)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Perry - Woodford (1870) (Volume ff:2456)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Allen - Woodford, recapitulation (1870) (Volume ff:2457)
  - Kentucky: Manufacturing: Adair - Woodford (1870) (Volume ff:2458)
  - Kentucky: Social Statistics: Adair - Woodford (1870) (Volume ff:2459)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Adair - Bell (1880) (Volume ff:2460)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Boone - Butler (1880) (Volume ff:2461)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Caldwell - Christian (1880) (Volume ff:2462)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Clark - Elliott (1880) (Volume ff:2463)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Estill - Grant (1880) (Volume ff:2464)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Graves - Harden (1880) (Volume ff:2465)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Harlan - Hopkins (1880) (Volume ff:2466)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Jackson - Lawrence (1880) (Volume ff:2467)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Lee - McLean (1880) (Volume ff:2468)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Madison - Mercer (1880) (Volume ff:2469)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Metcalf - Nicholas (1880) (Volume ff:2470)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Ohio - Powell (1880) (Volume ff:2471)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Pulaski - Shelby (1880) (Volume ff:2472)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Simpson - Union (1880) (Volume ff:2473)
  - Kentucky: Agriculture: Warren - Woodford (1880) (Volume ff:2474)
  - Kentucky: Defectives, delinquents, and dependents: Adair - Jackson (1880) (Volume ff:2475)
  - Kentucky: Defectives, delinquents, and dependents: Jefferson - Woodford (1880) (Volume ff:2476)
  - Kentucky: Manufacturing: Adair - Hopkins (1880) (Volume ff:2477)
  - Kentucky: Manufacturing: Jefferson - Woodford (1880) (Volume ff:2478)
- Louisiana Census Schedules, 1850, 1860, 1870, 1880, (12 volumes)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Ascension - Washington (1850) (Volume ff:2479)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Ascension - Winn (1860) (Volume ff:2481)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Ascension - Winn (1870) (Volume ff:2399)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Ascension - Winn, recapitulation (1870) (Volume ff:2482)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Ascension - Claiborne (1880) (Volume ff:2483)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Concordia - Lafourche (1880) (Volume ff:2484)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Lincoln - Sabine (1880) (Volume ff:2485)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: St. Bernard - Tensas (1880) (Volume ff:2486)
  - Louisiana: Agriculture: Terrebonne - Winn (1880) (Volume ff:2487)
  - Louisiana: Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes: Ascension - Winn (1880) (Volume ff:2488)
  - Louisiana: Manufacturing: Ascension - Winn (1880) (Volume ff:2489)
  - Louisiana: Social Statistics: Assumption - Washington (1850); Ascension - Winn (1860); Ascension - West Feliciana (1870) (Volume ff:2480)
- Montana Census Schedules, 1880, (1 volume)
  - Montana: Agriculture (1880) (Volume ff:2410)
- Nevada Census Schedules, 1880, (1 volume)
  - Nevada: Agriculture (1880) (Volume ff:2410)
- Tennessee Census Schedules, 1850, 1860, 1870, 1880, (36 volumes)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Anderson - Franklin (1850) (Volume ff:2490)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Gibson - Humphreys (1850) (Volume ff:2491)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Jackson - Monroe (1850) (Volume ff:2492)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Montgomery - Smith (1850) (Volume ff:2493)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Stewart - Wilson (1850) (Volume ff:2494)
  - Tennessee: Manufacturing: Anderson - Wilson (1850) (Volume ff:2495)
  - Tennessee: Social Statistics: Anderson - Wilson (1850) (Volume ff:2400)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Anderson - Fayette (1860) (Volume ff:2496)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Fentriss - Haywood (1860) (Volume ff:2497)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Henderson - McNairy (1860) (Volume ff:2498)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Macon - Rutherford (1860) (Volume ff:2499)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Scott - Wilson (1860) (Volume ff:2500)
  - Tennessee: Manufacturing: Monroe - Wilson (1860) (Volume ff:2501)
  - Tennessee: Social Statistics: Anderson - Wilson (1860) (Volume ff:2502)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Anderson - Dickson (1870) (Volume ff:2503)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Dyer - Hancock (1870) (Volume ff:2504)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Hardeman - Lawrence (1870) (Volume ff:2505)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Morgan - Sullivan (1870) (Volume ff:2506)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Lewis - Montgomery (1870) (Volume ff:2507)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Sumner - Wilson (1870) (Volume ff:2508)
  - Tennessee: Manufacturing: Anderson - Lewis (1870) (Volume ff:2509)
  - Tennessee: Social Statistics: Anderson - Wilson (1870) (Volume ff:2510)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Anderson - Carter (1880) (Volume ff:2511)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Cheatham - DeKalb (1880) (Volume ff:2512)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Dickson - Giles (1880) (Volume ff:2513)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Grainger - Hawkins (1880) (Volume ff:2514)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Haywood - Jefferson (1880) (Volume ff:2515)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Johnson - McNary (1880) (Volume ff:2516)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Moore - Robertson (1880) (Volume ff:2517)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Rutherford - Smith (1880) (Volume ff:2518)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Stewart - Warren (1880) (Volume ff:2519)
  - Tennessee: Agriculture: Washington - Wilson (1880) (Volume ff:2520)
  - Tennessee: Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes: Anderson - Hickman (1880) (Volume ff:2521)
  - Tennessee: Defective, dependent, and delinquent classes: Houston - Wilson (1880) (Volume ff:2522)
  - Tennessee: Manufacturing: Anderson - Lawrence (1880) (Volume ff:2523)
  - Tennessee: Manufacturing: Lewis - Wilson (1880) (Volume ff:2524)
- Virginia Census Schedules, 1860, (1 volume)
  - Virginia: Free inhabitants, slaves, deaths, agriculture, manufacturing, social statistics: Halifax County (1860) (Volume ff:2525)
- Wyoming Census Schedules, 1880, (1 volume)
  - Wyoming: Agriculture (1880) (Volume ff:2410)